Fritz Werner Papers
Fritz Werner Papers
1929-1965
Werner, Fritz.
1.0 linear ft.
Papers of the Austrian-American portrait painter. Collection contains correspondence, incoming, 1934-1965; drawings; photographs of his portraits; and printed material, including articles, clippings and exhibition catalogs, 1936-1964.
148746
Biographical History
Fritz Werner (1898-1994) was an Austrian-American painter best known for his portraits and still lifes. Born in Vienna, Austria, Werner studied at the National Academy of Arts in Munich, the Vienna Imperial Academy and the Academy des Beaux Arts in Paris. He spent several years in Argentina before settling in the United States, where he lived in California, New York, and Arizona.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Fritz Werner Papers consist of correspondence, articles, a few pieces of original artwork, clippings, exhibit material, and photographs of his portrait work.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Werner, Fritz -- Archives.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Austrian Americans.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Portrait painters -- United States.; Portrait painting -- United States -- 20th century.; Portrait painting, American.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Artists.; Painters.; Portrait-painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, 1934-1951; 1954-1965; 16 folders (Box 1)
  - Undated (Box 1)
- Articles
  - Articles about Werner's portraits, 1936; 1938,; 1950,; 1951,; 1964; 5 folders (Box 1)
- Artwork
  - Drawings by Werner, 52 items (Oversize 1)
- Clippings
  - Of Werner's portraits, 1964 (Box 1)
- Exhibits
  - 1936, 1943, 1954 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Of art exhibits
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Of portraits
    - Liselotte von Keller, 1929 (Box 2)
    - Senora Salas de Anchorerra, 1930 (Box 2)
    - Dr. Carlos Egger, 1931 (Box 2)
    - Maria Esther Puentes Falcon, 1931 (Box 2)
    - Dorothy Vits, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Christa Gabriele Greifs, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Susan Barbara, 1942 (Box 2)
    - William Wrigley, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Walter Brimson, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Mrs. David Howard Byrd, 1960; 2 items (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Pullman Louden, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Hilding Lindberg, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Molly Jackson, Undated (Box 2)
    - Women, small photos (Box 2)
    - Men, small photos (Box 2)
    - Women, medium photos (Box 2)
    - Men, medium photos (Box 2)
    - Women, large photos (Box 2)
    - Men, large photos (Box 2)
    - Women, oversize photos (Oversize 1)
    - Men, oversize photos (Oversize 1)
    - Werner's subjects (Box 2)